<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayes on Functionally Defined</title>
    <link>/tags/bayes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayes on Functionally Defined</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Allen Chang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/bayes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best of Styleforum’s What Are You Wearing Today Thread - 2018 Edition</title>
      <link>/posts/the-best-of-styleforum-s-what-are-you-wearing-today-thread-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-best-of-styleforum-s-what-are-you-wearing-today-thread-2018/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data Scraping Analyzing thumbs in 2017 and 2018 Hypothesis Testing Frequentist hypothesis testing Bayesian hypothesis testing  References   Introduction Happy New Year! For the second year now, I’ve returned to compile the most popular pictures from Styleforum’s ‘What Are You Wearing Today (WAYWT)’ thread. As a primer if you didn’t read last year’s post, the WAYWT thread is one of the most active and popular areas on the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting forum activity the Bayesian way</title>
      <link>/posts/forecasting-forum-activity-the-bayesian-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/forecasting-forum-activity-the-bayesian-way/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   Introduction I was reading through Google’s unofficial data science blog and came upon a post about Bayesian Structural Time Series Modeling and their bsts R package. I wanted to familiarize myself with time series approaches, as they’re relevant for business. I realized I had all the forum data that I had been scraping for the last year contained time series information built into it.
During my participation in the forum, I’ve noticed that the number of posts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Models for Ad Conversion Prediction</title>
      <link>/posts/a-summer-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-summer-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This summer I had the opportunity to do an internship in data science at the advertising technology company MediaMath. The experience was challenging, educational, and a lot of fun. My project was to investigate methods of probabilistic programming for ad conversion prediction and to deliver a viable method that could be used for production. I had the chance to write about the outcomes of my work and to be the first post in MediaMath&amp;rsquo;s new data science blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying styleforum posts using a Naive Bayes approach</title>
      <link>/posts/classifying-forum-classes-using-a-naive-bayes-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/classifying-forum-classes-using-a-naive-bayes-approach/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Text scraping Text mining Building the classifier Assessing classifier performance Referencess   Introduction The ways in which people talk about clothing can vary across different sub-populations. On styleforum, the two largest sub-populations are those that are interested in classic menswear versus those that are interested in streetwear. The forum itself is actually divided into these two sides. This posed an interesting question to me to determine if differences in the way that these two sides of the forum discuss clothes could be used to classify posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>