<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayes on Functionally Defined</title>
    <link>/tags/bayes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayes on Functionally Defined</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Allen Chang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/bayes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Models for Ad Conversion Prediction</title>
      <link>/posts/a-summer-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-summer-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This summer I had the opportunity to do an internship in data science at the advertising technology company MediaMath. The experience was challenging, educational, and a lot of fun. My project was to investigate methods of probabilistic programming for ad conversion prediction and to deliver a viable method that could be used for production. I also had the chance to write about the outcomes of my work and to be the first post in MediaMath&amp;rsquo;s new data science blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying styleforum posts using a Naive Bayes approach</title>
      <link>/posts/classifying-forum-classes-using-a-naive-bayes-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/classifying-forum-classes-using-a-naive-bayes-approach/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Text scraping Text mining Building the classifier Assessing classifier performance Referencess   Introduction The ways in which people talk about clothing can vary across different sub-populations. On styleforum, the two largest sub-populations are those that are interested in classic menswear versus those that are interested in streetwear. The forum itself is actually divided into these two sides. This posed an interesting question to me to determine if differences in the way that these two sides of the forum discuss clothes could be used to classify posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>