<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clothing on Functionally Defined</title>
    <link>/tags/clothing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clothing on Functionally Defined</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Allen Chang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/clothing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of fashion enthusiasts</title>
      <link>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-fashion-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-fashion-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed
Here’s the list of packages used..
library(rvest) library(tidyverse) library(stringr) library(tidytext) library(broom) library(lubridate) library(tm) library(igraph) library(ggraph) theme_set(theme_bw()) The first step was to pull text from all posts in the Saint Laurent Paris thread. If you’ve read my previous analyses, this follows the same scraping procedure as I’ve outlined in my random fashion thoughts post and my what are you wearing today post.
# scrape user posts url &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping the most popular fit pictures of 2017 from Styleforum’s “What are you wearing today” thread</title>
      <link>/posts/web-scraping-the-2017-most-popular-fit-pictures-on-styleforum-s-what-are-you-wearing-today-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/web-scraping-the-2017-most-popular-fit-pictures-on-styleforum-s-what-are-you-wearing-today-thread/</guid>
      <description>One of the main draws of Styleforum is it’s “What Are You Wearing Today” thread. In it, users get to show off their clothes in pictures, other users can give “likes” to deem a fit exemplary (if you’ve ever opened up Instagram this concept is probably not too foreign for you). I wanted to see not only which posts were given the most likes in 2017, but I also wanted to download the photo(s) from each fit to upload into a photo album to share with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network analysis of my daily clothing choices</title>
      <link>/posts/daily_clothing_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/daily_clothing_network/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation of my previous analysis on tracking preferences in clothing choices (part 1 is here). The inspiration for this post came about after re-reading David Robinson’s network analysis of the movie love actually and realizing that a similar approach could be applied to my sparse network of clothing choices. I found additional help by working through the Network Analysis course on Datacamp.
As per usual, these were the packages used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking preferences in my daily clothing choices</title>
      <link>/posts/daily_wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/daily_wear/</guid>
      <description>Clothing is one of my hobbies. I spend a fair amount of time thinking, searching for, and talking about clothes with some of my friends. This led me to ask whether I could analyze my own clothing preferences over a period of time starting from Sept. 15 - Dec. 15th. While I’m consciously aware of some of my preferences (I wear a lot of black and clothes from Belgian born designers), I was hoping that I might see other patterns of choices that I had not picked up on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>