<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functionally Defined</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Functionally Defined</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Allen Chang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Just how good is TensorFlow at categorizing images anyways?</title>
      <link>/posts/just-how-good-is-tensorflow-at-categorizing-images-anyways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/just-how-good-is-tensorflow-at-categorizing-images-anyways/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Okay, that title is a bit of a rhetorical question. Everyone knows that TensorFlow is great at catstrikethrough textegorizing images. For the purposes of my self-interest and curiosity though, I wanted to see the magic with my own eyes.
I should say straight from the start that this post won&amp;rsquo;t contain any new code, and the overall goal is more for me to play around in the sandbox and learn more about how image classification models work (which I think is equally as fun!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Models for Ad Conversion Prediction</title>
      <link>/posts/a-summer-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-summer-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This summer I had the opportunity to do an internship in data science at the advertising technology company MediaMath. The experience was challenging, educational, and a lot of fun. My project was to investigate methods of probabilistic programming for ad conversion prediction and to deliver a viable method that could be used for production. I had the chance to write about the outcomes of my work and to be the first post in MediaMath&amp;rsquo;s new data science blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I like</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description>Because bookmarks bars get too full
Essential reading on the use of cognitive maps
R ggplot visualization examples
arranging multiple plots - useful for scientific figures
picking visualization colors
wes anderson movie color palletes
alternative to tikz diagrams
functions for lists! + associated tutorial
Emacs keybindings references
Bayes fast AB testing
linear regression with gibbs
intro to bayes with stan
Books my bible
Statistics probability cheatsheet
0 math intro to mcmc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping korean fried chicken restaurants</title>
      <link>/posts/mapping-korean-fried-chicken-restaurants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mapping-korean-fried-chicken-restaurants/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data pre-processing Mapping the data Map customization Refs   Introduction A change of pace! I realized that almost all of my posts thus far have been clothing related, so I decided to pivot and work with another of my interests; fried chicken. Fried chicken is irresistable, and my apartment in Boston is close to a number of korean fried chicken restaurants. For this analysis, I wanted to visualize how a specific chain of korean fried chicken restaurants, Bonchon, were distributed across the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying styleforum posts using a Naive Bayes approach</title>
      <link>/posts/classifying-forum-classes-using-a-naive-bayes-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/classifying-forum-classes-using-a-naive-bayes-approach/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Text scraping Text mining Building the classifier Assessing classifier performance Referencess   Introduction The ways in which people talk about clothing can vary across different sub-populations. On styleforum, the two largest sub-populations are those that are interested in classic menswear versus those that are interested in streetwear. The forum itself is actually divided into these two sides. This posed an interesting question to me to determine if differences in the way that these two sides of the forum discuss clothes could be used to classify posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing color frequency of clothing choices</title>
      <link>/posts/visualizing-color-frequency-of-clothing-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/visualizing-color-frequency-of-clothing-choices/</guid>
      <description>Data Preprocessing Constructing a grid of colors Visualizing color frequencies References   In a preivous post, I visualizled color choices in clothing using slope charts and histograms. This time I wanted to get a bit more creative. In this post I’m going to explore how color frequencies in my clothing choices change across months by using waffle charts.
As usual, to start here’s a list of the packages that I used in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a ggplot theme for my scientific publications</title>
      <link>/posts/making-a-ggplot-theme-for-my-scientific-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/making-a-ggplot-theme-for-my-scientific-publications/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Koundinya Desiraju. This is a place for me to store themes so I have a convenient place to look when I inevitably forget.
library(ggplot2) library(ggthemes) library(grid) theme_pub &amp;lt;- function(base_size=10, base_family=&amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot;) { library(grid) library(ggthemes) (theme_foundation(base_size=base_size, base_family=base_family) + theme(plot.title = element_text(face = &amp;quot;bold&amp;quot;, size = rel(1.2), hjust = 0.5), text = element_text(), panel.background = element_rect(colour = NA), plot.background = element_rect(colour = NA), panel.border = element_rect(colour = NA), axis.title = element_text(face = &amp;quot;bold&amp;quot;, size = rel(1)), axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the forcats package to easily reorder factors </title>
      <link>/posts/using-the-forcats-package-to-easily-reorder-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/using-the-forcats-package-to-easily-reorder-factors/</guid>
      <description>Like all programmers, I strive to make my code efficient and easily readable. I hope that the results are somewhat close to those two ideals, but I know that there are always better ways to code things (this xkcd hits alarmingly close to home for me…)
(source: xkcd)
That being said, I’m always happy to stumble into R packages or snippets of code that can help me become more efficient in writing code and I do my best to remind myself to try and use these methods in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive clothing networks</title>
      <link>/posts/interactive-clothing-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/interactive-clothing-networks/</guid>
      <description>This is the 3rd part of my analysis on daily clothing choices (part 1 and part 2). In this post I’m going to be testing out the the threejs package and creating interactive networks using the graphjs function. I will also be using David Robinson’s gganimate package to create an animated timeline of my clothing choices.
As usual, here’s the packages used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of fashion enthusiasts</title>
      <link>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-fashion-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-fashion-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>Like most hobbyists, clothing enthusiasts tend to have strong opinions. In this post I wanted to look at how these opinions changed across time using sentiment analysis and text mining. My dataset of choice was user posts from the Saint Laurent Paris thread on Styleforum. The data was comprised of text from user posts beginning in 2012 and continuing up until today.
As usual, here’s the list of packages used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping the most popular fit pictures of 2017 from Styleforum’s “What are you wearing today” thread</title>
      <link>/posts/web-scraping-the-2017-most-popular-fit-pictures-on-styleforum-s-what-are-you-wearing-today-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/web-scraping-the-2017-most-popular-fit-pictures-on-styleforum-s-what-are-you-wearing-today-thread/</guid>
      <description>One of the main draws of Styleforum is it’s “What Are You Wearing Today” thread. In it, users get to show off their clothes in pictures, other users can give “likes” to deem a fit exemplary (if you’ve ever opened up Instagram this concept is probably not too foreign for you). I wanted to see not only which posts were given the most likes in 2017, but I also wanted to download the photo(s) from each fit to upload into a photo album to share with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text scraping Styleforum’s “Random Fashion Thoughts” thread</title>
      <link>/posts/text-scraping-styleforum-s-random-fashion-thoughts-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/text-scraping-styleforum-s-random-fashion-thoughts-thread/</guid>
      <description>Styleforum’s “Random fashion thoughts” is one of the most popular sections of the website. It’s a thread where users can talk about almost anything they want regarding clothing and fashion. Every once in awhile the thread gets so long that the moderators opt to close it off and create a new post. The most recent iteration, RFT II, was recently retired so I decided to give myself a weekend project and run some text analysis on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network analysis of my daily clothing choices</title>
      <link>/posts/daily_clothing_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/daily_clothing_network/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation of my previous analysis on tracking preferences in clothing choices (part 1 is here). The inspiration for this post came about after re-reading David Robinson’s network analysis of the movie love actually and realizing that a similar approach could be applied to my sparse network of clothing choices. I found additional help by working through the Network Analysis course on Datacamp.
As per usual, these were the packages used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking preferences in my daily clothing choices</title>
      <link>/posts/daily_wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/daily_wear/</guid>
      <description>Clothing is one of my hobbies. I spend a fair amount of time thinking, searching for, and talking about clothes with some of my friends. This led me to ask whether I could analyze my own clothing preferences over a period of time starting from Sept. 15 - Dec. 15th. While I’m consciously aware of some of my preferences (I wear a lot of black and clothes from Belgian born designers), I was hoping that I might see other patterns of choices that I had not picked up on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing home states for Top Chef contestants in R</title>
      <link>/posts/visualizing-home-states-for-top-chef-contestants-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/visualizing-home-states-for-top-chef-contestants-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Each season of Top Chef is something that I look forward to every year and it’s one of the only shows that my girlfriend and I will make an hour of time for every week to watch. To my delight, this season two of my favorite writers Tom Haberstroh and Kevin Arnovitz have started a weekly podcast called Pack Your Knives to discuss each episode and share their love of Top Chef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. candidate in Cognitive Neuroscience at Boston University. Inside the lab, I think about why humans learn differently from one another. Outside the lab, I scour the internet for vintage clothes and eat as much Korean fried chicken as I can afford after buying vintage clothes.
This site is a work in progress, so please forgive any and all broken things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>