<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on Functionally Defined</title>
    <link>/tags/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on Functionally Defined</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Allen Chang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of fashion enthusiasts</title>
      <link>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-fashion-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-fashion-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>Like most hobbyists, clothing enthusiasts tend to have strong opinions. In this post I wanted to look at how these opinions changed across time using sentiment analysis and text mining. My dataset of choice was user posts from the Saint Laurent Paris thread on Styleforum. The data was comprised of text from user posts beginning in 2012 and continuing up until today.
As usual, here’s the list of packages used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text scraping Styleforum’s “Random Fashion Thoughts” thread</title>
      <link>/posts/text-scraping-styleforum-s-random-fashion-thoughts-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/text-scraping-styleforum-s-random-fashion-thoughts-thread/</guid>
      <description>Styleforum’s “Random fashion thoughts” is one of the most popular sections of the website. It’s a thread where users can talk about almost anything they want regarding clothing and fashion. Every once in awhile the thread gets so long that the moderators opt to close it off and create a new post. The most recent iteration, RFT II, was recently retired so I decided to give myself a weekend project and run some text analysis on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking preferences in my daily clothing choices</title>
      <link>/posts/daily_wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/daily_wear/</guid>
      <description>Clothing is one of my hobbies. I spend a fair amount of time thinking, searching for, and talking about clothes with some of my friends. This led me to ask whether I could analyze my own clothing preferences over a period of time starting from Sept. 15 - Dec. 15th. While I’m consciously aware of some of my preferences (I wear a lot of black and clothes from Belgian born designers), I was hoping that I might see other patterns of choices that I had not picked up on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing home states for Top Chef contestants in R</title>
      <link>/posts/visualizing-home-states-for-top-chef-contestants-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/visualizing-home-states-for-top-chef-contestants-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Each season of Top Chef is something that I look forward to every year and it’s one of the only shows that my girlfriend and I will make an hour of time for every week to watch. To my delight, this season two of my favorite writers Tom Haberstroh and Kevin Arnovitz have started a weekly podcast called Pack Your Knives to discuss each episode and share their love of Top Chef.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>